

### CONTACTS

www.dilettagoglia.com

in linkedin.com/in/dilettagoglia/

+39 340 320 4546

github.com/dilettagoglia

live: diletta.goglia\_2

@dilettagoglia

facebook.com/diletta.goglia.71

@diletta\_goglia

Diletta Goglia

diletta.goglia@gmail.com

d.goglia@studenti.unipi.it

postmaster@pec.dilettagoglia.com

### **LANGUAGES**

### Italian (native)

English (CEFR level B2 First)

French (CEFR level A1)

### **EXAMS GRADES**

### Master Degree

- Social and Ethical Issues in IT: 30/30
- Intelligent Systems for Pattern Recognition: 30 cum laude
- Semantic Web: 28/30

#### **Bachelor Degree**

- Final Thesis: 110/110
- Digital Libraries: 30/30
- Philosophy of science: 30 cum laude
- Graphic design: 30/30
- Databases and Web design: 29/30
- Text encoding: 28/30
- Ethics of communication: 30/30
- Web design and development: 30 cum laude

# DILETTA GOGLIA

### MSc STUDENT IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

### **PROFILE**

I am 24 years old, I am an Italian national and I am currently living in Pisa. I got a Bachelor Degree in A.Y. 2018 in Digital Humanities (Informatica Umanistica) at University of Pisa and now I am a student of the Master Degree in Artificial Intelligence, at the Department of Computer Science of the same university.

I have working experience as teaching assistant, as Web Designer and Developer, Social Media Manager and Content Creator.

During my studies I gained deep expertise in Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Neural Network models. I also became really interested in the ethic field of Artificial Intelligence and in its complex social implications.

In my private life I am an activist for some relevant social ... I am Buddhist and bodybuilding competitor. I am also a huge reader! I love books about roboethic, religions and personal development.

### HARD SKILLS

I am a Full Stack Developer expert in:

### Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Neural Networks

- Bayesian learning
- Graphical and generative models (HMM, MRF)
- Dynamic Bayesian networks
- Deep learning techniques (CNN, Autoencoders, DBN, etc.)
- Deep learning for machine vision and signal processing
- Advanced neural networks (recurrent, recursive, ...) for learning and forecasting
- Reinforcement learning
- Signal processing and time-series analysis
- Image processing, filters and visual feature detectors
- ML and DL libraries & tools: Keras, Tensorflow, MatLab

### • Web Development & Desing

- HTML, CSS, XML, XHTML, XSL-T, RelaxNG, JavaScript
- Client-side lanuages: JavaScript, TypeScript
- Server-side languages: Python, PHP
- Others: Flask, Google API, AJAX call, jQuery, JSON
- MySQL for relational DBMS
- Graphic design: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

### • Semantic Web and Linked Open Data

- RDF, RSFS, OWL, SPARQL
- Communication
  - CMS management (Wordpress)
  - Social Network Management
  - Professional Writing: Ebook, scientific papers

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- D. Goglia, <u>Amplifying bias, automating racism. Ethically framing the issue of algorithmic</u> <u>discrimination</u>, July 2020, University of Pisa
- D. Goglia, <u>Linked Open Data per il Cultural Heritage italiano: conversione e pubblicazione</u> <u>nel Semantic Web del Fondo antico del Comune di Novi Ligure</u>, May 2019, University of Pisa

### **EDUCATION**

In progress... Enrollment: AY. 2019/20 MSc Student in <u>Artificial Intelligence</u>
Master programme in Computer Science

University of Pisa

Enrollment: AY. 2015/16 Graduation: AY. 2017/18 Bachelor Degree in <u>Digital Humanities</u>

University of Pisa Final grade: 110/110

2011 - 2015

High school diploma

Viceo scientifico G. Galilei, Civitavecchia

Final grade: 95/100

### WORKING EXPERIENCE

SEP-DEC 2020

#### Teaching assistant

University of Pisa

Teaching Javascript & Typescript at the course of Laboratory I, to first year students of the Bachelor Degree in Computer Science

OCT 2020

#### **Social Media Editor**

💡 Internet Festival 2020 edition event, Pisa

Member of the content creators staff for the event; real time promotion of the activities through web and social.

MAR 2020

#### Technical support to Informatic Section staff of Medical School

Santa Chiara Hospital, Pisa See below "Won Rankings" section.

Support the operators at the IT centre of Medicine. Interrupted due to COVID-19.

OCT 2019 Social Media Editor

💡 "Internet Festival 2019 edition" event, Pisa

Member of the content creators staff for the event; real time promotion of the activities through web and social.

NOV 2018 - SEP 2019

### Technical assistance to University staff

University of Pisa

See below "Won Rankings" section.

 $Technical-administrative \ and \ teaching \ staff \ assistance (``Teledidattica digitale \ evoluta'' \ project) \ and \ support for \ post-production \ of \ multimedia \ content$ 

JUN 2018

#### Web designer

FICT agency Memphremagog, Lucca.

Javascript programming, user interface improvements, graphic intervention on the company business website.

MAY - JUN 2018

### Web Designer, Promoter, Social Media Manager

"Vintage", Pisa (food & restaurant services sector)

Website development and social network pages management for activity promoting.

MAR - MAY 2018

### Digital publishing – internship

University of Pisa, "Laboratorio di Cultura Digitale" (curricular internship)

Development and writing of an interacting ebook in english to promote an activity for the project "A Digital Journey in Europe, Erasmus+". Main aim: ICT integration in schools, and best practice sharing between students about digital learning.

### HOBBY AND ACTIVITIES

Coming soon...

Labodif course: Istituto di ricerca e formazione nello studio delle differenze di genere

2020

Member of <u>Associazione Italiana per l'Intelligenza Artificiale (AIXIA)</u>: Istituto di ricerca e formazione nello studio delle differenze di

2020

Supporter of Algorithmic Justice League (AJL) movement

2018-20

Supporter of Fourth-Wave Feminist movement

2020

Activist for <u>SenzAtomica</u>: "trasformare lo spirito umano per un mondo libero da armi nucleari".

2019

Member of Soka Gakkai International (SGI): Istituto Buddista Italiano per la pace, la cultura e l'educazione

2017-18

**Training seminars on equal rights and opportunities: "categorie, diritti, discriminazioni",** by CIRQUE (Centro Interuniversitario di Ricerca Queer).

### **PORTFOLIO**

### PROJECTS FOR UNIVERSITY OF PISA

#### 2020 Gated Recurrent Neural Network for timeseries prediction

Long-Short Term Memory (LSTM) to predict energy consumption from multivariate timeseries.

#### 2020 Hidden Markov Model for regime detection

 $Python\ analysis\ of\ time series\ to\ cluster\ ranges\ of\ consumption,\ using\ Hidden\ Markov\ Models\ with\ Gaussian\ emissions.$ 

#### 2020 Image processing with SIFT algorithm

Python analysis on images using SIFT algorithm.

#### 2020 OWL Ontology in Turtle Notation

Semantic modelling project: building an ontology with languages recommended by W3C for Semantic Web

### 2020 IoT application

"SmartBin, a Smart Solution for Garbage Management" for improvement on garbage management system: an intelligent bin that monitors itself.

- Devices: Arduino Uno + Weight sensor HX711 + Load cell + RFID Reader MC522 + Ultrasonic sensor HC-SR04 + WiFi Module ESP8266 + Servomotor + RGB Led
- Server: Python Flask
- Database: MySQL
- Web Interface: Chart.js, AJAX call, Google Maps API

#### 2020 "The AI (in)justice league"

A report on Algorithmic Bias: why it is ethically problematic and how to handle it.

Link to the event talks

#### 2020 "Embodied intelligence: a review"

The question of embodiment in behaviour-based robots.

#### 2018 Web app

Statistic and descriptive analysis of medical data as result of a Data Journalism investigation about supplement consumption in Italy.

Data are extract, cleaned up and organized in CSV tables, managed through a database SQL. Query API are in PHP.

The implemented software receives data through AJAX and return them in Json format to a script that processes them and show them in a client-readable format (charts displayed in a user interface).

### 2017 Natural Language Processing analysis

Human-language features extraction from corpora and statistic analysis with NLTK.

### 2017 Text Encoding

Digital encoding of some extract of the book "La condizione postmediale", using standards XML TEI P5, XSL stilesheets, XHTML, XMLS, RelaxNG, DTD. Main task of the annotation: Named Entity Recognition. Also, a user interface is implemented for navigation of content.

### 2016 Interactive website

Website with a JavaSctipt implementation of an interactive CV builder

### PROJECTS FOR OTHER COMPANIES

### 2018 Website for "Vintage Pub"

Pisa

Planning and development of a website to promote a local activity ("food and restaurant" field).

### 2018 Website improvements for "Memphremagog" company

Lucca

Graphic intervention on the company business website: Javascript programming, and some user interface improvements and the company business website and the company

### **GRANTS AND AWARDS**

- 2020 | Collaboration assignment granted by the IT department of University of Pisa
- 2020 | University of Pisa performance ranking, for ICT assistance job position at Medical School
- 2018 | University of Pisa performance ranking, for ICT technical staff assistance job position
- 2018 | Study Grant as selected student for the training event "Make in Italy"

# **CERTIFICATES**

| Coming soon | Google Digital Training  |
|-------------|--|
| 2018        | Samsung Innovation Camp  |
| 2018        | Digital Food Communication, Confcommercio Lucca  |
| 2018        | First Certificate in English (FCE): Upper-Intermediate-2 (Livello B2 del CEFR), certified by University of Pisa      |
| 2018        | Make In Italy Festival: digital world meets Italian manufacturing.   |
| 2014        | BLS (Basic Life Support), Croce Rossa Italiana - Comitato area Provinciale di Roma                                   |
| 2010        | Attestation de mérite pour l'étude de la langue française, Association des Membres de l'Ordre des Palmes Académiques |

## TRAINING COURSES AND ATTENDED SEMINARS

| 2020 | Al Week: Public lecture series on Artificial Intelligence, organizer: SFU's School of Computing Science (online)  |
|------|---|
| 2020 | <b>How AI and Machine Learning can Transform Organizations,</b> <i>organizer:</i> Skyl.ai, Machine Learning Automation For Unstructured Data (online)   |
| 2020 | What does diversity & inclusion mean in 2020? #GirlBossNight, organizer: Girls In Tech Australia (online)   |
| 2020 | Explaining the workings of a Deep Neural Network, organizer: Al3 Science Discovery Network (Al3SD) (online)   |
| 2020 | Mitigating Bias in Analytics, organizer: Women In Analytics (WIA) (online). Here I had a really stimulating discussion in the Zoom Rooms with some of the participants. Directly confronting with people living in the U.S. is literally an eye-opener to know the impact of the current discriminations by algorithms. |
| 2018 | <u>Samsung Innovation Camp</u> : 25 hours training for digital marketing, communications, data analytics, cyber education and innovative use of technologies.   |
| 2018 | Microsoft seminar at University of Pisa for using <b>Office 2016 Pro Plus</b> instruments and <b>cloud Office 365</b> services.   |
| 2018 | Make In Italy Festival 2018, Thiene (VI): digital world meets Italian manufacturing: tools and technologies for the transition to 4.0 of small / medium-sized business. I won a study grant to have the opportunity to partecipate.   |
| 2018 | <u>Digital Food Communication</u> , Confcommercio Lucca: using digital instruments for client communications and web promotion of business.   |
|      |   |

In compliance with the Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned decree

Last update: October 2020